www.github.com/jafranswa

Objective

My goals are delivering a timely quality product, a focus on expanding my skills to meet future needs, and finding a roll that challenges my growth as a software engineer. I have experience in Agile, Cloud, REST, Java/Python web applications, and DevOps. I am a mindful team player, and communicator with a passion for knowledge sharing.

Skills

Languages: Java, C#, JavaScript, Groovy, Python, SQL

Technologies:

Java - Spring/SpringBoot, ThymeLeaf, Hibernate, Junit, Mockito, PowerMock, REST, SOA, Microservices, SQL, MongoDB, TDD, BDD

C# - FrameWork, .Net Core, XUnit, Telerik JustMock, TDD

Python - Flask, SQLAlchemy, Jinja2, Gunicorn, Redis

JavaScript - NPM, React, Node, MongoDB, NoSQL

DevOps CICD - Shared Pipeline Library (Groovy), Scripted Pipeline, Declarative Pipeline, Infrastructure as Code, Jenkins, Cloud Bees Core, Blue Ocean, Artifactory, Ansible, SonarQube, Selenium, SauceLabs, Azure Devops

Developer Tools - Agile, IntelliJ, Eclipse, PyCharm, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, MAMP, mySQL, Maven, Gradle, Anaconda, Jira, Git, Github Enterprise

Experience



SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, VETERAINS UNITED HOME LOAN, ST LOUIS, MO – 2020-PRESENT

Notable Projects:

Encompass Plugins Suite

- Maintained and expanded features of plugin suite for Encompass Loan Origination Application
- Introduced TDD into legacy codebase, decoupled code using best practices & eliminated anti patterns
- Migrated source control from TFVC to Git

Source Control Guild

• Participated in weekly mobbing on modernizing source control processes to facilitate Devops & XP culture



ASSOCIATE PROGRAMMER ANALYST, EXPRESS SCRIPTS, ST LOUIS, MO – 2018-2020

Notable Projects:

Jenkins / Groovy - Shared Pipeline Library:

- Supported -Jenkins, Ansible, ELRelease, Docker integrations and codebase
- Assisted in 50+ teams getting automated build to production through guidance, training, & pairing
- Adding features to the Shared Pipeline Library in direct support of on boarding teams such as: Semver Version enforcing, Pega deployment support, etc...
- Modularize shared library (BDD) and participated in design/creation of second generation multimaster Jenkins/Cloud Bees Core and Shared Library
- End to End testing of the Jenkins Shared Pipeline Library dictating all CICD steps (build, test, deploy, etc..) & maintaining suite of applications utilizing each run time environment deployed during this End to End testing
- Increased Shared Pipeline code test coverage from 10% to 54% utilizing Spock Framework

contact: Linkedin

www.github.com/jafranswa

Breaking monolithic Java applications into entities for SOA

• Refactor entities in monolithic Java/Spring app, & creating domain specific apps to replace entity in monolith

Testing Framework - REST Micro-services used for QA testing:

- Maintained and built upon Java/Spring REST app/QA framework used for company wide End to End coverage
- Sonar cube bug fixes, modularized codebase using best practices, design patterns, and TDD
- Maintained and built upon JavaScript/Node/MongoDB-NoSQL Service used for company wide End to End coverage
- Designed/Reworked documentation & Git Flow for inner sourcing Pull Request process, & reduced user support
- Rotational Scrum leader lead sprint, sprint planing, triage support, hold standup, facilitate alignment
- Built POC Spring Cloud Load-balancer for balancing traffic between multiple Selenium Grids running in a Docker Swarm, and between other in house micro-services



CONTRACTOR, EXPRESS SCRIPTS, ST LOUIS, MO – 2018 - 2018

Notable Projects:

<u>Regression Testing Application</u>:

- Build MVC web app upon existing command line app in python for easier tester adoption
- Expand coverage from 3 MITRE ATTA&CK MATRIX strategies to 56 strategies



LEAD INSTRUCTOR, LAUNCHCODE, ST LOUIS, MO - 2018 - 2018

Responsibilities:

- Taught lecture-stye classroom of 150 students Object-Oriented Programing & MVC in Python
- Produced and delivered slide lectures on OOP geared towards best practices and clean code
- Daily live coding exercises demonstrating/reinforcing curriculum content, and taking Q&A
- Coordinated 12 Teaching assistants on curriculum and students progress to ensure student retention



TEACHING ASSISTANT, LAUNCHCODE, ST LOUIS, MO – 2018 - 2020S

Responsibilities:

• Lead lab group of 15 students facilitating technical, & communication growth

Education

LaunchCode, St Louis, MO – Certificate, CS - 2017

University of Nebraska Lincoln 3.5gpa, Lincoln, NE – Master of Fine Arts, Sculpture - 2013 Southern Illinois University Edwardsville, Edwardsville, IL – Bachelor of Fine Arts, Sculpture - 2008